CURRICULUM VITAE BENJAMIN DAVID FEDORUK

205-66 King St. W.
Oshawa ON L1H 1A6
(807) 630-5512
benjamin.fedoruk@ontariotechu.net
www.benfedoruk.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in noticing patterns in everyday life. I find pure mathematics to be highly pattern-based, and strongly believe that applying a similar problem-solving approach and abstract mindset will solve real world problems. My recent research interest has been in infodemiology, through connections to evolutionary graph theory. I am also highly interested in mathematical logic.

EDUCATION

2020 – present **B.Sc. Student**, Applied and Industrial Mathematics

Ontario Tech University

2016 – 2020 International Baccalaureate Certificate Program

Superior Collegiate and Vocational Institute

PUBLICATIONS

(1) Fedoruk B, Nelson H, Frost R, Fucile Ladouceur K. The Plebeian Algorithm: a democratic approach to censorship and moderation. JMIR For Res. 2021 Dec 21; 5(12):e32427. doi: 10.2196/32427.

BLOG POSTS

(1) Fedoruk B. Natural philosophy in the ancient and early modern worlds. SciComm Blog, STEM Fellowship. 2022 Mar 25.

EXPERIENCE

2022 – present Chief Data Officer

STEM Fellowship (Data Science Committee)

2022 – present **Copy Editor**

STEM Fellowship Journal

2022 Event Coordinator

STEM Fellowship (Data Science Committee)

2021 – 2022 **Program Management Team Lead**

STEM Fellowship (Data Science Committee)

OTHER POSITIONS

2022 – present	Co-Founder and President
	Northern Shores Innovation Institute
2021 - 2022	Data Analyst
	AutoGuardian by SmartCone
2017 - 2020	Vice President
	Regional Multicultural Youth Council

WORKSHOPS HOSTED

2021 Nov	Fighting for the Truth: Using the Plebeian Algorithm to Combat Social
	Media Misinformation (30 attendees)
2021 Oct	A Democratic World Wide Web: An Introduction and Implementation of the
	Plebeian Algorithm to Freely Combat Misinformation (1600 attendees)

HONOURS AND AWARDS

2022	NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award
2022	M2C2 ICUBE Third Place Award
2022	Accessible Mobility: Towards a Zero-Barrier Mobility Challenge Third Place
2021	Brilliant Catalyst Challenge for Rural Canada Winner
2021	JMIR Infodemic Innovation Award
2021	#Challenge4ClimateAction: Datathon Stream Second Place
2020	Ontario Scholar
2020	Kiwanis Club of Westfort Scholarship

This curriculum vitae is true and accurate as of 4 June 2022.